<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Zero to ASIC Course</title>
    <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Zero to ASIC Course</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Printing my first ASIC&#39;s GDS files</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/printing_gds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:46:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/printing_gds/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to try plotting or printing the GDS files from my first ASIC for a while, and finally I&amp;rsquo;ve had some time to have a play. I used KLayout because it&amp;rsquo;s easy to change colours, show and hide layers, and export to a high resolution PNG.
I want to make a poster with 3 pictures inside:
 The whole chip, Zoomed into the VGA clock macro, Zoomed into the standard cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Caravel GPIO</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/understanding_caravel_gpio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 13:36:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/understanding_caravel_gpio/</guid>
      <description>When I was first testing my designs inside Caravel, I was quite confused about all the GPIO options.
 Each pin has a range of options that can be configured by firmware running on the RISCV processor. Each pin can be driven from the processor or your custom design. The outputs have separate output enable lines for bi-directional signalling.  I put together an experiment where I tried the most important options and checked the results in a simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last minute DRC fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/last_minute_drc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:47:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/last_minute_drc/</guid>
      <description>The story of the first Open Source ASIC shuttle continues!
A few of the applicants to the first shuttle were recently contacted by efabless - they had discovered some DRC issues that couldn&amp;rsquo;t be waived by the foundry.
In my recent interview with Tim Edwards, he mentioned that Google are paying for a license of Calibre - another swiss army ASIC tool like Magic. This is to help make sure that the OpenLANE DRC hasn&amp;rsquo;t missed anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Tim Edwards - what happens between ASIC submission and sending to Skywater?</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-tim-edwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 16:08:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-tim-edwards/</guid>
      <description>In this interview I talk with Tim Edwards from eFabless. He is their vice president of analog and platform.
We mostly talked about what needs to happen before they send the final files to Skywater.
A lot of the work is infrastructure:
 fetching files, compositing IDs, generating fill layers, a final DRC run.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Lakshmi S - PLL design</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-lakshmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 16:08:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-lakshmi/</guid>
      <description>In this interview I talk with Lakshmi S about their shuttle submission.
As well as convering what a PLL is and its component parts, we also answered some interesting questions from the twitter community:
 how long things take to design, what is fun and what is frustrating, how to change the PLL&amp;rsquo;s response, why design a integrated loop filter, process corners and ngspice post silicon testing.  The repository is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview With Diego Hernando</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-diego/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 18:06:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-diego/</guid>
      <description>In this interview I talk with Diego Hernando about their ASIC submission.
They have been working on some analog blocks; mostly op-amps but also including a PLL from another designer.
We discuss the difference between digital and analog design, the tools, simulation, layout and testing.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the repository
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Attribution</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/image_attribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:57:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/image_attribution/</guid>
      <description>Image attributions for images used on this website.
Image from Mohamed Shalan
Image from Caravel Datasheet
Image from RFCafe
Image from Caravel Datasheet
Image from Wikipedia
Image from Components 101
Image from Wikipedia
Image from WhaTech
Image from Technocrazed
Image from Zeptobars
Image from Lattice Semiconductor
Image from Lattice Semiconductor
Image from M. Rovitto
Image from Texplained
Image from Wikimedia
Image from Europractice
Image from VLSI Systems by Mead &amp;amp; Conway</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASIC submitted</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/asic_submitted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 18:07:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/asic_submitted/</guid>
      <description>Wow! What a journey. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to announce our submission is in and accepted. Now we have a long wait to see if it works!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of the final design. The outer edge and the block at the bottom are all part of Caravel, the standard chip format that everyone on the shuttle has to use. It includes a RISCV processor, RAM, UART, a wishbone bus and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Arya Reais-Parsi - FPGA fabric</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-arya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 16:08:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-arya/</guid>
      <description>In this interview I talk with Arya Reais-Parsi about their shuttle submission. They are working with a group of students to create Open Source FPGA fabric that can be put on an ASIC and configured with yosys/nextpnr.
The repository is here.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview With Sylvain &#39;tnt&#39; Munaut: USB peripherals</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-tnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 16:08:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-tnt/</guid>
      <description>In this interview I talk with Sylvain &amp;lsquo;tnt&amp;rsquo; Munaut about his Google/Skywater ASIC application.
The design is especially interesting to me because of the way it merges the SRAM blocks with the logic. This has been a major challenge in my own design.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the repository
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview With Vladimir Milovanović - spectrometer with Chisel</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-vladimir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 16:08:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/interview-with-vladimir/</guid>
      <description>In this interview I talk with Vladimir Milovanović about putting a spectrometer on the Google/Skywater/Efabless ASIC shuttle.
He created the design using Chisel.
The repository is here.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDS Artwork</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/gds-artwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 17:58:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/gds-artwork/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought the artwork people put in the top layer of their chips was cool. Do a google image search for chip artwork to see some more fun examples.
While waiting for some toolchain bugs to get ironed out I&amp;rsquo;ve made a tool to help me make logos. It can take SVG or PNG input and makes a GDS2 file output. These files can then be merged together to create the final layout for the ASIC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Can We Fit on an ASIC?</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/how-much-can-we-fit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 20:00:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/how-much-can-we-fit/</guid>
      <description>The Google / Skywater shuttle reserves about 10 square mm (10 million square microns) of space for your design.
This comparison that Mohamed from efabless put together shows the various areas (and time to generate the GDS2 files) of some popular designs.
We could fit in about 10 picorv32 RISCV cores!
My designs I currently have 3 designs ready to add to the multi project harness:
   Name Square microns How many would fit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VGA clock</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/vga_clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 19:13:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/vga_clock/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the first projects I hardened using OpenLane.
It shows the time on an LCD panel. It will be part of my first tapeout.
After running the OpenLane ASIC flow, it results in a design that uses 180x180 microns (32000 square microns). As we have about 10e6 square microns in the user project area of the Google shuttle, I could potentially put about 300 of these on the ASIC!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi Project Harness</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/multi-project-harness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 14:54:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/multi-project-harness/</guid>
      <description>The Google/Skywater Shuttle has about 10 square mm of space for your project. This sounds tiny but is actually HUGE for many beginner projects. Read this post to find out what you could fit in the user space.
For the Zero to ASIC course, I want to aggregate all your designs together into that area, so we need to do some extra bits:
 Multiplex all the inputs and outputs of your project to the GPIO pins of the Caravel harness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackaday #remoticon talk</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/remoticon-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/remoticon-talk/</guid>
      <description>I recently presented a demo/presentation for Hackaday&amp;rsquo;s #remoticon.
 slides from the talk presentation tools    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inverter</title>
      <link>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/inverter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.zerotoasiccourse.com/post/inverter/</guid>
      <description>A standard cell is a building block that contains some basic digital or analogue functionality. These blocks are then tiled together to make the final design.
Since finding out about the Skywater PDK, I wanted to try drawing my own &amp;lsquo;standard cell&amp;rsquo; using the Skywater transistor models.
An inverter is one of the simplest and even that was quite difficult! As you can see below it contains an N and P type MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
